Guide to the Walter L. Pforzheimer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- November 2000 Acquisition, 46.46; (53 boxes) + 5 broadside folders, 1 object storage item, 1 roll
  - Historical Manuscripts
    - United States, Revolutionary War
      - Mifflin, Thomas: autograph letter, signed, to Eldridge Gerry, 21 Nov 1776 (Box 17)
      - American Revolution-miscellany, May 2 1777, undated; 3 (Box 17)
      - Mulligan, Hercules, 1776, undated (Box 17)
      - Purviance, Samuel, Jr., 4 May 1777 (Box 17)
      - Short, John: confession (copy), undated
      - Tallmadge, Benjamin, 1780, 1811 (Box 17)
      - Washington, George: 3 letters in the matter of Mrs. Provoost to Governor Livingston, 1782 (Box 17)
      - Washington, George: autograph letter, signed, to Major Tallmadge, 20 Nov 1778 (Box 17)
      - Washington, George: autograph letter, signed, to Colonel Elias Dayton, 26 Jul 1777
      - Washington letters: photographs, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Washington, George: printed, undated (Box 17)
      - Letters: photostats, undated
      - Notes and reviews, undated (Box 17)
      - Schedule of receipts, 25 Dec 1815 (Box 17)
      - Letters and documents, circa 1763-1895 (Box 17)
      - Letters and documents: photostats, undated (Box 17)
    - United States, Civil War
      - Letters, 1847-1929; 2 (Box 17)
      - Printed material, 1864, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Photographs [reproductions], undated (Box 17)
      - Photostats, undated (Box 17)
      - Poster: A Northern Voice for the Dissolution of the Union, undated
      - Bousal, Rebecca Wright, 1912, undated (Box 17)
      - Boyd, Belle (Confederate Spy), undated (Box 17)
      - Bramlette, Thomas E., 22 Sep 1861 (Box 17)
      - Cushman, Pauline, undated (Box 17)
      - Fremont, J. C., Apr 18-19 1862 (Box 17)
      - Gormandy, Major General, 23 Oct 1861 (Box 17)
      - Greenhow, Rose O'Neal (USA), undated (Box 17)
      - Hammond, James P., 1863 (Box 17)
      - I spy (game), 1893 (Box 17)
      - Pinkerton, Alan, 12 Oct 1862 (Box 17)
      - Roberts, Jonathan, 11 Jan 1862 (Box 17)
      - [Roscrans?], undated (Box 17)
      - Seward, Frederick W., 7 Feb 1862 (Box 17)
      - Sherman, John, undated (Box 17)
      - Stonewall Jackson, 26 Jul 1861 (Box 17)
      - Stringfellow, Frank, 26 Feb 1864, undated (Box 17)
      - Townsend, George Alfred: How Wilkes Booth crossed the Potomac, photocopy, undated (Box 17)
      - Map of Confederate Spy Country, 1861-65, compiled by Brigadier General William A Tidwell, Fairfax, Virginia, 1979
    - France
      - D'Argenson, Comte Marc Pierre de Voyer, 1743 (Box 17)
      - Mademoiselle La Chevaliere, 1787 (Box 17)
      - D'Eon de Beaumont, Chavalier, 1777 (Box 17)
      - English naval forces, 1746, undated (Box 17)
      - Fouché, Joseph du de Otante, undated (Box 17)
      - De Fougery, Chevalier, undated (Box 17)
      - La Dehors, Marie Courtin de. Autograph letter, signed. Photocopy, [1773] May 3 (Box 17)
        Accession number 1959 genm 1003-a
        Related to Molière
      - French Revolution-spies, 29 Jul 1792 (Box 17)
      - Documents: manuscript, including accounts and reports, circa 1740-1881 (Box 17)
      - The defense of Gracchus Babeuf; Eight, undated (Box 17)
      - Reproductions from the Andrew Mellon Collection
        Photocopy of engraving depicting William Edward Peary
      - 18th century French code, undated
    - Russia
      - Alphabets, 1993, undated (Box 17)
      - Certificates, 1942, undated; 3 (Box 17)
      - Communism. The Moral Factor; article, 1959 (Box 17)
      - Fricke, Oscar: The Dzerzhinkey Commune: Birth of the Soviet 35mm Camera Industry, article, Apr 1979 (Box 17)
      - KGB. 70th Anniversary Medal, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Klub Kremlin, undated (Box 17)
      - Matshazi, Mawela: Ministry of Defence certificate, 20 Jun 1799 (Box 17)
      - Medals, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 17)
      - Printed material, 1954, 1994 (Box 17)
      - 3rd Reconnaissance Diversionary Group: special designation, insignia, undated (Box 17)
    - Codes and Ciphers
      - Cardinal Richelieu, 1623 (Box 17)
      - Charles V, Emperor, 1548, 1965 (Box 17)
      - Cipher, 1781, 1965 (Box 17)
      - Einstein, Albert: TLS to Howard L. McVitty, 22 Sep 1943 (Box 17)
      - Friedman, W. F.: Notes on Code Words, Aug-Sep 1932 (Box 17)
      - Lewin, Ronald: codes and ciphers, 1981-1984; 2 (Box 17)
      - Orders, Sep 1743 (Box 17)
      - Philip II, King of Spain, undated
      - Seventeenth century codes, undated
      - Substitution cipher, 18th century (Box 17)
      - Ciphers: miscellaneous, undated
  - Military Intelligence and Personal Papers
    - Catalogues, undated (Box 18)
    - Book dealers United States, undated (Box 18)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 18)
    - Invoices, receipts and correspondence, circa 1955-1992; 9 (Box 18)
    - Invoices, receipts and correspondence, circa 1955-1992; 5 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, 1936, undated (Box 18)
    - Property rights in letters, 1939, undated (Box 18)
    - Interview with Walter Pforzheimer and Laurence Houston: transcript, 17 Nov 1982 (Box 18)
    - Notes re. government, undated (Box 18)
    - Copyright and scholarship article, 1940 (Box 18)
    - Essay on sonnets and particularly those by William Shakespeare, 9 Feb 1930 (Box 18)
    - Music: its growth and development, undated; 2 (Box 18)
    - Engravings: Yale University, 1831, 1838 (Box 18)
    - Yale Debate Posters, undated
    - Beard, Daniel Carter, undated (Box 18)
    - Clippings, 1991 (Box 18)
    - Peary, Robert, Jul-Aug 1908 (Box 18)
    - Grolier Club speech and exhibit, 1972 (Box 18)
    - Grolier Club working papers, undated; 4 (Box 18)
    - American literature notes, 1928-29 (Box 18)
    - Congressional ranking 82nd Congress, 1952 (Box 18)
    - Booklist for buying abroad, undated (Box 18)
    - Library list, undated (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, circa 1954-1997; 5 (Box 19)
    - Westchester Country Club, 1939 (Box 19)
    - Property of W. L. Pforzheimer, undated; 3 (Box 19)
    - Rudyard Kipling burial service in Westminster Abbey, 1936 (Box 19)
    - Library exhibit, undated (Box 19)
    - Photographs, undated; 3 (Box 19)
    - Certificates, 1947, undated (Box 19)
    - Appraisal: Herman W. Liebert, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Bookshelves, 1959 (Box 19)
    - Address by Walter L. Pforzheimer, advisor on Special Collections, Yale Univeristy Library to the Institute on Documentation and Copyright Law, 21 May 1963 (Box 19)
    - Exhibit of writings of Walter L. Pforzheimer, Sep 1972 (Box 19)
    - Giacometti, A. Bartlett, 1979-1986 (Box 19)
    - Presidential inauguration, 1957; 2 (Box 19)
    - Catalogs, circa 1951-1966; 3 (Box 19)
    - Pforzheimer family history, undated (Box 19)
    - Passport, 1956 (Box 19)
    - "What can I do for an old gentleman", undated; 2 (Box 19)
    - Copyright and scholarship, 1941; 2 (Box 19)
    - Letters (photocopies), undated; 2 (Box 19)
    - Jefferson, Thomas, 1813 (Box 19)
    - Mabie, Hamilton Wright, 1892 (Box 19)
    - Mann, Horace, 1830 (Box 19)
    - Robinson, Joseph, circa 1700 (Box 19)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1883, 1916 (Box 19)
    - Talford, Thomas, 1840-1865 (Box 19)
    - Account books, circa 1889; 4 (Box 20)
    - An economic myopia, with postcards, undated (Box 20)
    - Copyright protection for the performing artist in his interpretive rendition, by Walter L. Pforzheimer, 1938 (Box 20)
    - History of common law copyright. Early statutory copyright., 1937 (Box 20)
      Copyright cases in the United States Supreme Court, by Walter L. Pforzheimer
    - Proposed copyright legislation in the United States, by Walter L. Pforzheimer, 1937 (Box 20)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 20)
    - Grammar School Diploma, 1897
    - Letters, notes, in Italian, 1922 (Box 20)
    - Sir John Masterman interview (2 audiotapes, 1/4 inch), 4 Apr 1972; 2 (Box 20)
    - Dr. Pforzheimer; speech to SOC grad. party, duplicate (videotape, 1/2 inch), 11 Dec 1975 (Box 20)
    - CIA (3 microfilm reels), undated; 3 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous letters and printed material, 1923-1961 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, circa 1928-1985 (Box 21)
    - Book list, undated (Box 21)
    - Photographs: Walter Pforzheimer, undated (Box 21)
    - Hensey, Florence, undated (Box 21)
    - Democratic National Party, 1972 (Box 21)
    - Birthday: Walter Pforzheimer, undated (Box 21)
    - Yale University commencement: photographs of honorary degree recipients, Jun 1955 (Box 21)
    - Accountability of colleges and universities, 1995 (Box 21)
    - Speech: Newt Gingrich, undated (Box 21)
    - View of old building on William Street, undated (Box 21)
    - André, John, undated (Box 21)
    - Adams, Samuel: to Dr. Hitchcock, 21 Dec 1778 (Box 21)
    - Hammerton, John Alexander, 1923-1924 (Box 21)
    - Envelope, undated (Box 21)
    - Deland, Margaret Wade Campbell, 1906-1937 (Box 21)
    - Myers, Gustavus: Final paragraph in the history of bigotry..., undated (Box 21)
    - Dodge, Mary Mapes, 10 Dec 1892 (Box 21)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1976-1993 (Box 21)
    - Pforzheimer family vital records, circa 1872-1973 (Box 21)
    - Printed material, 1968-1969, undated (Box 21)
    - Hoover, Harry, 25 Dec 1928 (Box 21)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 20 Oct 1928 (Box 21)
    - Philby, Harold Adrian Russell: correspondence Homer G. Mueller (of Aramco), circa 1962 (Box 21)
    - Cole, Walter: Sweet Adeline, undated (Box 21)
    - Mexico-Guerillas, 1863 (Box 21)
    - Dreyfus, Robert: Kafka's Banner, 1994 (Box 21)
    - In Memoriam of Allen W. Dulles: album, 29 Jan 1969 (Box 21)
    - Copyright report, 1963 (Box 21)
    - CIA-reports, 1956, 1958, undated (Box 21)
    - CIA, 2 (Box 21)
    - CIA-Cuba photographs, 1962 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, 1859-1932 (Box 21)
    - Letters-Horace Mann (reproductions), undated; 2 (Box 21)
    - NASA pins, undated; 7 (Box 22)
    - Russian pin, 1973 (Box 22)
    - Richard Sorge 1895-1944: stamps, undated (Box 22)
    - Hughes Glomar Explorer: medal, undated (Box 22)
    - Hughes Glomar Explorer: rock, undated (Box 22)
    - Molière: correspondence, circa 1977-1978 (Box 23)
    - Molière: bibliography, undated (Box 23)
    - Molière: plays: photostats, undated; 7 (Box 23)
    - Molière: notebooks, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - Notes, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - Notebooks, undated; 3 (Box 25)
    - Photostats, undated; 9 (Box 26)
    - Photostats, undated; 3 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1961, 1977, undated (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, circa 1934-1986 (Box 26)
    - Grolier club exhibit labels, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - Notes, undated (Box 26)
    - Molière British Museum catalog, Aug 1930 (Box 26)
    - Molière: bibliographic material, undated (Box 26)
    - Jasinski, R.: Molière. Connaissance des lettres, printed version, 1969 (Box 26)
    - Molière: book cover, undated (Box 26)
    - Molière: engravings, undated; 9 (Box 26)
    - Molière: engravings, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - Sir Francis Walsingham, engraving, from the collection of Walpole, undated
    - Molière: correspondence and notes, 1929-1931, undated; 2 (Box 26)
    - Molière: medals, undated; 8 (Box 27)
    - Chatham, undated (Box 28)
    - Clinton, George, 1783 (Box 28)
    - Guiteau, Charles, 22 Dec 1881 (Box 28)
    - Walker, L. P., 11 Sep 1861 (Box 28)
    - Lord Sommers, 24 Jan 1692 (Box 28)
    - Bryd, Belle: photograph, undated (Box 28)
    - Pen knife, undated (Box 28)
    - Deakin, Sir William, 6 Apr 1980 (Box 28)
    - Arnold, Matthew, 3 Oct (Box 28)
    - Correspondence and catalogs, 1927-1936 (Box 28)
    - General Bloomfield, 1814 (Box 28)
    - de Gallitet, G., undated (Box 28)
    - Dreyfus, Alfred, undated (Box 28)
    - Tallmadge, Benjamin: engraving, undated (Box 28)
    - Spies and Intelligence: exhibit, 1960 (Box 28)
    - Molière: letters and documents, undated (Box 28)
    - World War II: Germany, 1945, undated (Box 28)
    - Notes and printed material, undated (Box 28)
    - Pforzheimer, Jeanne Bock: will, 10 Sep 1957 (Box 28)
    - Will, 1955-1966; 2 (Box 28)
    - King George II, 26 Sep 1738 (Box 28)
    - Molière: miscellaneous, undated (Box 28)
    - Molière: reproductions, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Bejart, Armande: receipt, 1686? (Box 28)
    - Coyal, Antoine: receipt and engraving, 1699, undated (Box 28)
    - Ingres, Jean Auguste: portrait of Molière, undated (Box 28)
    - Leloir, Louis: engravings of scenes from plays, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Martin, Louis Aimè: autograph letter, signed, to "Mon cher ami", undated (Box 28)
    - Mignard, Pierre: receipt and engraving, 1683, undated (Box 28)
    - Quinault, Philippe: receipt and engraving, undated (Box 28)
    - Moland, Louise Émile Diendonnè: autograph letter, signed, to "Monsieur", undated (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous invoices, photographs, notes and correspondence, 1965-1984, undated (Box 28)
    - Newspaper Photostats, rolled, undated
    - Mask of Treachery Promotional Poster, undated (Box 28)
    - Unidentified material, rolled
    - "Party Life." Poster of Ape and Woman, undated (Box 28)
    - Unidentified material, rolled
    - Chinese Propaganda Poster, rolled, 1980
    - Comic Mock-Up of CIA seal, rolled, undated
    - Art Shop label, undated
    - Glass slides
    - Bibliographic binders, undated; 4 (Box 29)
    - French Historical
      - Molière: reproductions, 1664-1669 (Box 30)
      - Molière: reproductions, 1670-1679 (Box 30)
      - Molière: reproductions, 1680-1698 (Box 30)
      - Molière: reproductions, 1700-1798 (Box 30)
      - Molière: reproductions, 1801-1930s (Box 30)
      - Molière: reproductions, 1663-1707 (Box 30)
      - Molière and other Comics: reproductions, 1569-1663 (Box 30)
      - Pencil Drawn Cartoon about Pforzheimer, undated (Box 30)
      - Wood Mounted Scene of Party-Goers, undated (Box 30)
      - Colet, Louise, Le Monument de Moliere: Poeme, 1843 (Box 30)
    - Catalog cards
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (3 card files) (Box 31)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 32)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 33)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 34)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 35)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 36)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 37)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 38)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 39)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (1 card file) (Box 40)
      - Catalog Cards, undated; (4 card files) (Box 41)
      - Catalog Cards, cancelled checks, bookplates, undated; (1 card file, 2 boxes) (Box 42)
      - Catalog cards, undated; (4 card files) (Box 43)
  - Oversize
    - Moliere, engraved by P.M. Alix, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Sir Francis Walsingham, engraving, from the collection of Walpole, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Silk screen print by Colonel Randolph Abel, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Aerial sketch of a harbor city, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Roger Caseman, lithograph, 1916 (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Intelligence, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Yale buildings, prints and etchings, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Newspaper clips and letter, 1847 (Box 44 Oversize)
    - The defense of Gracchus Babeuf; Eight Reproductions from the Andrew Mellon Collection; Photocopy of engraving depicting William Edward Peary, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - 18th century French code, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Revolutionary War Letters, Photostats, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Bryan, Daniel; affidavit regarding the Battle of Saratoga, 27 Dec 1852 (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Hale, Nathan, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Confession of John Short (copy), undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Bissel, Sgt. Daniel; Report of mission to New York, 1781-1782 (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Concerning the trial, execution and various matters connected with the histoy of Major John André, 1786; 2 (Box 44 Oversize)
    - André, John - miscellaneous, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - André, John; Iconography print of self-portrait miniature, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - André, John; Iconography, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Intelligence, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Aitken, James, alias John the Painter, undated (Box 44 Oversize)
    - Intelligence, Newsprint under Eisenhower, undated (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Netherlands, World War II Underground Press[?], 1942 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Het Dagblad, 1945 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Het Parool, 1941-1945; 2 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Nederland in Oorlogstijd. Orgaan van het Rijiksinstituut voor Oorlogstijd, 1946-1948; 2 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Speer, Albert: certificates, 1938, 1942 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Moscow News. Purge trials. Proceedings, 1937-1938 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - German security posters, undated (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Newspapers, 1936 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Engraving, Moliere Portrait, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Engraving, Hedouin, Edmond. Eau Forte: Illustrations pour la theatre de Moliere, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Engraving, Bayard, Emile: Estampes pour les oeuvres de Moliere, engraved by Teyssonieres, Lalauze, and Dupont, 1883 (Box 46 Oversize)
    - The Unfortunate Death of Major André, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Campaign Poster, Joseph Clark Baldwin, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Cipher, 18th century codes, Seventeenth Century Codes, 1792, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Washington, George: autograph letter, signed, to Colonel Elias Dayton, 26 Jul 1777 (Box 46 Oversize)
    - British Intelligence. Financial Accounts of Queen Anne for Secret Service, 1703, 1705 (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Secret Service Money in Columbia Centinel, 2 Apr 1803 (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Letter and Portrait of Alexander Hamilton, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Berlin, from Der Presussische Finanzminister [Prussian Finance Minister], Jul 1939 (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Goldene Buch der Flieger, Nazi German Airforce 'Golden Book of Fliers' Award, undated (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Stamp Book, undated; 2 (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Engravings, Collection de Beaux Livres: images of French and other Authors' bindings, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Engravings, Moliere with "Sganarelle ou le Cocu Imaginaire" images, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Engravings, Depictions of Moliere, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Engravings, Coypel, Charles Antoine: unbound. Suite d'estampes des principaux sujets des Comedies de Moliere, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Civil War: letter to Lincoln regarding F. William Walker, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Civil War: Harper's Weekly photocopies, printed, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Photograph - Civil War Scouts (Scouts and Guides of the Potomac), undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Hooke, Nathaniel, undated (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Peoples' Republic of China Atlas, CIA, Nov 1971 (Box 47 Oversize)
    - White, Stewart Edward: removed from "Our Unseen Guest", 1873-1946 (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Photograph - Berlin, American Commission to Negotiate Peace, Feb 1919 (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Grammar School Diploma, 1897 (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Yale Debate posters, undated (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Les Chevaliers: Mademoiselle d'Eon de Beaumont. Fencing Match between d'Eon de Beaumont and de Saint George, engraving, undated (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Poster: A Northern Voice for the Dissolution of the Union, undated (Box 48 Oversize)
    - The Capture of Major André, by A.B. Durand, undated (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Dreyfus, Captain Alfred, undated (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Codes and Ciphers, Phillip II of Spain, 12 Jan 1597 (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Newspaper Photostats, rolled, undated; (1 item) (Box 49 Oversize)
    - Mask of Treachery Promotional Poster, rolled, undated; (1 item) (Box 49 Oversize)
    - "Party Life." Poster of Ape and Woman, rolled, undated; (1 item) (Box 49 Oversize)
    - Chinese Propaganda Poster, rolled, 1980; (1 item) (Box 49 Oversize)
    - Comic Mock-Up of CIA seal, rolled, undated; (1 item) (Box 49 Oversize)
    - Art Shop label, undated; (1 item) (Box 49 Oversize)
    - Aerial Photographs of Auschwitz and Birkenau, Aug 1944 (Box 50 Broadside folder)
    - CIA Promotional Posters, undated (Box 51 Broadside folder)
    - Aerial Photographs, undated (Box 52 Broadside folder)
    - Wendell L. Willkie poster, undated (Box 53 Broadside folder)
    - Exhibition on Spies and Intelligence, undated (Box 54 Broadside folder)
    - Map of Confederate Spy Country, 1861-65 Compiled by Brigadier General William A Tidwell, Fairfax, Virginia, 1979 (Box 55 Roll)
  - Restricted Fragile
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. For further information consult Access Services.
    - World Trade Center fragments, 2001; (1 box) (Box 56)
    - Russian [Soviet?] Dzerzhinskij flag, (1 item) (Box 57)
    - Soviet camera, (1 item) (Box 58)
    - Autochromes, circa 1910; (6 items) (Box 59)
      Images of Pforzheimer family members
    - Serving dish, Meissen porcelain, from Adlerhorst, Adolf Hitler's headquarters in Berchtesgaden, (1 item) (Box 60 Object storage)
      Taken from the Adlerhorst by Captain Walter Pforzheimer in the first week of May 1945, as the war was ending
- April 2003 Acquisition, 85.71; (89 boxes) + 4 broadside folders, 2 cold storage packages, 5 framed art storage items, 3 object storage items
  Boxes and folders are unarranged. Box contents have not been verified.
  Contents are similar to November 2000 Acquisition, including manuscripts and related materials collected by Pforzheimer concerning the history of military intelligence; materials relating to Pforzheimer's intelligence career; documentation of Pforzheimer's book and manuscript collecting; postage stamps collected by him; photographic materials, prints, and visual art; audio and video recordings; computer disks; and objects.
  - Military Intelligence and Personal Papers
    - Intelligence papers (Box 61)
    - Correspondence, photographs (Box 62)
    - Mixed papers, intelligence papers, photographs, correspondence (Box 63)
    - Manuscripts (Box 64)
    - Clippings, appointment books (Box 65)
    - Clippings, mixed papers (Box 66)
    - Correspondence, mixed papers (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, mixed papers (Box 68)
    - Photographs, travel diaries, intelligence-related papers (Box 69)
    - Mixed papers, correspondence (Box 70)
    - Correspondence, financial papers (Box 71)
    - Family papers (Box 72)
    - Photographs, albums (Box 73)
    - Personal papers (Box 74)
    - Personal papers, correspondence (Box 75)
    - Photographs, personal papers, professional papers (Box 76)
    - Photographs, personal papers (Box 77)
    - Personal papers, professional papers (Box 78)
    - Intelligence-related papers (Box 79)
    - Intelligence-related papers (Box 80)
    - Intelligence-related papers (Box 81)
    - Personal papers (Box 82)
    - Personal papers, professional papers (Box 83)
    - Personal papers (Box 84)
    - Personal papers, committee papers (Box 85)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 86)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 87)
    - Personal papers (Box 88)
    - Personal papers (Box 89)
    - Photographs, daily planner (Box 90)
    - Daily planner, photographs (Box 91)
    - Photographs, family papers (Box 92)
    - Personal papers (Box 93)
    - Personal papers (Box 94)
    - Intelligence papers (Box 95)
    - Professional papers, personal papers photographs (Box 96)
    - Family papers, photographs, prints (Box 97)
    - Personal papers, family papers (Box 98)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 99)
    - Personal papers, family photographs (Box 100)
    - Professional papers (Box 101)
    - Professional papers (Box 102)
    - Professional papers (Box 103)
    - Professional papers (Box 104)
    - Professional papers (Box 105)
    - Card catalog, financial papers (Box 106)
    - Framed items (Box 107)
    - Framed items (Box 108)
    - Photo albums (Box 109)
    - Photo albums (Box 110)